<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<document-metadata version="1.0" xmlns="http://breeze.macromedia.com/ns/document-metadata" generator="Adobe Captivate 8">
<document-info>
	<title>Video Fundamentals for Staff: Knowing Your Audience</title>
	<summary>This presentation is all about providing consultants with the affective skills they need to asses and gauge faculty responses to technical consultations.</summary>
	<author>Joshua M. Harder</author>
	<keywords>Adobe Captivate Project Video Fundamentals for Staff: Knowing Your Audience</keywords>
	<view-link href="index.html?slide={position}"/>
</document-info>
<section type="slide" position="1">
	<title>Knowing Your Audience Title Slide</title>

	<content>
	<text>Knowing Your Audience</text>
</content>

	<related-content>Hello and welcome to another module in the &quot;Video consultations with Faculty&quot; series.; I&apos;m Josh harder and I will be walking you through this module wihich is titled &quot;Knowing Your Audience&quot;.; Just to review, your navigation buttons will always be located in the badger red, DoIT banner.; On this page there is only a next button, but on upcoming pages you may find Next, Previous, and Submit buttons.; Use these buttons to naviage through this module.</related-content>
</section>
<section type="slide" position="2">
	<title>Learning Outcomes</title>

	<content>
	<text>Explain video terminology using more than one analogyObserve and respond to patron’s visual cues of confusion if present.Provide alternative explanations to terminology if patronDescribe video manipulation processes at a rate that allows for patron absorption.</text>
</content>
</section>
<section type="slide" position="3">
	<title>Review: Saving Time by Testing</title>

	<content></content>

	<related-content>If you are going through these modules in sequence, your last module covered why we make samples of our videos.; This module also covered best practices for making samples.</related-content>
</section>
<section type="slide" position="4">
	<title>Preview: Knowing Your Audience</title>

	<content>
	<text>Different ways to describe videoMonitoring reactions to your consultative styleGauging client reactionsBeing thoughtful about how your message is received</text>
</content>

	<related-content>For this module you will be working with two faculty members who need a consultation on video essentials.; I’ve highligted a few key areas of focus, but overall this module is about being conscious in the moment and realizing how you are being perceived by the client with whom you are working.</related-content>
</section>
<section type="slide" position="5">
	<title></title>

	<content></content>
</section>
<section type="slide" position="6">
	<title>Setting the Stage</title>

	<content>
	<text>New consultant with back-to-back consultations covering video basics.Your choices will affect the faculty member’s “Grumpy Meter”.More Points = More GrumpyLess Points = Less GrumpyYour goal is to keep the Grumpy Meter low.</text>

	<text>$$page_grumpy_meter$$</text>

	<text>$$card_grumpy_meter$$</text>
</content>

	<related-content>You are a new consultant and you just book two consultations with faculty members.; They are back-to-back consults on video basics. As you work with faculty members, your responses will affect their “Grumpy Meter”.; If you make the faculty member grumpy the meter will go up. If you make the faculty member happy, the meter will go down.; If you give a satisfactory response the meter will not move. Your goal is to keep the grumpy meter as low as possible.; Your other goal is to experiment with the responses and see why certain responses make the faculty members grumpy or happy.; As you are going through the scenario think about how Dr. Page and Dr. Card react differently.</related-content>
</section>
<section type="slide" position="7">
	<title>Getting to Know Dr. Page</title>

	<content>
	<text>New to technologyNot comfortable with computersLikes to learn by reading and making a plan firstHas been told by her department that she needs to modernize her curriculumHas never done anyting with video beforeTeaching hybrid (online/f2f ) course and wants to create small videos to introduce each module to post in LMS</text>

	<text>$$page_grumpy_meter$$</text>
</content>

	<related-content>Here are the traits of Dr. Page. She is very new to computing.; Dr. Page is extremely hesitant to use computers and to experiment because she might break them.; Please keep this in mind as you are working through the scenario.</related-content>
</section>
<section type="slide" position="8">
	<title>Getting to Know Dr. Card</title>

	<content>
	<text>Pretty savvy with computers.Setup desktop email application single-handedlyLearns by doingOften uses iPhone to make videos of nephews, but usually has a hard time posting them onlineKnows that video takes a lot of work, but is excited to do narrated PowerPoints for online class</text>

	<text>$$card_grumpy_meter$$</text>
</content>

	<related-content>Here are the traits of Dr. Card. She has been around computers for a while but has never really worked with video.; She is excited to get started and has read some blog posts about doing narrated PowerPoints.; Dr. Card usually dives into tech projects but sometimes gets stuck and frustrated about not knowing the terms to search for on Google when she hits a roadblock.</related-content>
</section>
<section type="slide" position="9">
	<title>Interview with Dr. Page</title>

	<content>
	<text>Dr. Page walks through the door about 10 minutes late. She is talking about getting stuck in a meeting and apologizing. You quickly figure out that Dr. Page does not have a laptop. After a little more conversation you find out she is not good with computers and is being asked by her department to modernize the course.It’s time to get to work and figure out what will work best for Dr. Page.</text>

	<text>$$page_grumpy_meter$$</text>
</content>
</section>
<section type="slide" position="10">
	<title>Select Work Area</title>

	<content></content>
</section>
<section type="slide" position="11">
	<title>At computer, faculty co-pilot,you are pilot</title>

	<content>
	<text>As you sit down, you turn on the computer and open a few programs at a quick pace. This flusters the Dr. Page and makes her feel uncomfortable. She asks you if this can be just a conversation.You thought having Dr. Page watch while you use the computer would be a good way for her to learn. Unfortunately, the description of Dr. Page was pointing toward her needing to build up to sitting at the computer. Dr. Page prefers having a conversation over “geeking out” right away.</text>

	<text>$$page_grumpy_meter$$</text>
</content>
</section>
<section type="slide" position="12">
	<title>At computer, faculty pilot, you are co-pilot</title>

	<content>
	<text>Faculty member very reluctantly sits down at the computer. She looks horribly uncomfortable and wants to keep handing over the keyboard and mouse to you. She  eventually asks if this can just be a conversation.You thought that the only way for someone to learn is to do it themselves. This assumes that everyone has a preference to learn this way.</text>

	<text>$$page_grumpy_meter$$</text>
</content>
</section>
<section type="slide" position="13">
	<title>No computer, just a conversation</title>

	<content>
	<text>The faculty member gives you a reassuring smile and gets out her notepad and pen, so she can take notes.Good job! You correctly identified Dr. Page’s perferred mode of learning. She is here to take it all in and the will evaluate the information before jumping on a computer.Although this may go against how you like to learn, it’s important to acknowledge and appropriately assess how others like to learn and to not defulat to your own preferences.</text>

	<text>$$page_grumpy_meter$$</text>
</content>
</section>
<section type="slide" position="14">
	<title>Starting with the Basics</title>

	<content>
	<text>You recall your training and want to lay the foundation by describing the fundatmentals. You start with pixels.Dr. Page settles in for a good coversation about video basics. She is excited to learn more about the building blocks.</text>

	<text>$$page_grumpy_meter$$</text>
</content>

	<related-content>Now that you have gotten an understanding of the importance of understanding a person’s learning preference, it is time to figure out the best way to describe principles.; There are many factors that go into knowing the best way to describe a concept to someone. How much are they paying attention? What is their skill level?; How deep does their understanding need to be to get the project done? What types of tools will they be using? And many more questions.</related-content>
</section>
<section type="slide" position="15">
	<title>Pixels: Select How to Describe</title>

	<content></content>
</section>
<section type="slide" position="16">
	<title>A pixel is a physical point</title>

	<content>
	<text>Dr. Page looks at you with utter confusion and needs further explanation.Although this response is technically accurate, it is too, well, technical. Never use a consultation as an opportunity to display what you know. You should take all that you know and work hard on translating it instead.</text>

	<text>$$page_grumpy_meter$$</text>
</content>

	<related-content>Think about your initial interacitons with Dr. Page. Think more deeply about how she would respond to this kind of explanation.; Does this technical description fit her demeanor when it comes to technology?</related-content>
</section>
<section type="slide" position="17">
	<title>A minute area of illumination</title>

	<content>
	<text>Dr. Page looks at you and her eyes have glazed over slightly. You can tell she has no idea what you are talking about.This response is still technical, but not too technical. You are using phrases that most people have encountered. Everyone knows screens, images, and light.</text>

	<text>$$page_grumpy_meter$$</text>
</content>

	<related-content>Even thought these phrases are common, Dr. Page does not even know what she needs to know.; It still confuses her. In other words, even a little bit of “tech speak” is too much for some people.</related-content>
</section>
<section type="slide" position="18">
	<title>Dots used to make a picture</title>

	<content>
	<text>Dr. Page completely understands and is fully engaged. You even take this opportunity to ask her if she has heard of HD TVs. She says yes and you explain that they are HD because the have more dots. “Ah, now I get,” she exclaims.</text>

	<text>$$page_grumpy_meter$$</text>
</content>

	<related-content>For Dr. Page, this is the perfect response. She is not here to learn every detail about videos.; She just needs to know the essentials and this is the right amount of technical info.</related-content>
</section>
<section type="slide" position="19">
	<title>Grumpy Meter Check</title>

	<content>
	<text>This is a quick check on Dr. Page’s Grumpy meter. Please remember, the higher the number, the grumpier she is.</text>

	<text>$$page_grumpy_meter$$</text>
</content>
</section>
<section type="slide" position="20">
	<title>Pixels: Select How to Describe</title>

	<content></content>
</section>
<section type="slide" position="21">
	<title>Fast</title>

	<content>
	<text>Dr. Page is almost instantly flustered and continually asks you to repeat yourself.Cognitive overload is a major concern when you start talking to fast. It takes a while to process new information and if you are quickly moving from one subject to the next, your client may not have learned the last concept.</text>

	<text>$$page_grumpy_meter$$</text>
</content>
</section>
<section type="slide" position="22">
	<title>Slow</title>

	<content>
	<text>Dr. Page is making quick notes of many of the concepts you are relating to her. She nods, showing understanding.A slow rate may be just right for complete novices, but annoying for clients with some skills.</text>

	<text>$$page_grumpy_meter$$</text>
</content>
</section>
<section type="slide" position="23">
	<title>Steady</title>

	<content>
	<text>Even though you think you are speaking slow enough, Dr. Page is still frantically scribbling notes and sighing with frutration.Some times steady is just right and some times it is too fast.</text>

	<text>$$page_grumpy_meter$$</text>
</content>
</section>
<section type="slide" position="24">
	<title>Grumpy Meter Check</title>

	<content>
	<text>This is a quick check on Dr. Page’s Grumpy meter. Please remember, the higher the number, the grumpier she is.</text>

	<text>$$page_grumpy_meter$$</text>
</content>
</section>
<section type="slide" position="25">
	<title>Getting to Know Dr. Card</title>

	<content>
	<text>As you move from your consultation with Dr. Card please remember the following about her:Pretty savvy with computersSetup desktop email application single-handedlyLearns by doingOften uses iPhone to make videos of grandkids, but usually has a hard time posting them onlineKnows that video takes a lot of work, but is excited to do narrated PowerPoints for online class</text>

	<text>$$card_grumpy_meter$$</text>
</content>
</section>
<section type="slide" position="26">
	<title>Select Work Area</title>

	<content></content>
</section>
<section type="slide" position="27">
	<title>At computer, faculty co-pilot,you are pilot</title>

	<content>
	<text>You sit down and turn on the computer and open a few programs at a quick pace. This makes Dr. Card excited and ready to go, but she makes a comment about how he learns from doing.Keep in mind that people who learn by doing like to be in charge. Having to watch could be frustrating to someone who needs to have the tactile sensation of doing a task to truly learn it.</text>

	<text>$$card_grumpy_meter$$</text>
</content>
</section>
<section type="slide" position="28">
	<title>At computer, faculty pilot, you are co-pilot</title>

	<content>
	<text>Dr. Card gladly sits down at the computer. She  excited to be at the helm and start learning. Good job! You identified her preferred way of learning.Figuring out learning preferences is an important conversation to have before you get started. Everyone has a different modality of learning that suits them best. Forcing them into another modality may make teaching harder than it needs to be.</text>

	<text>$$card_grumpy_meter$$</text>
</content>
</section>
<section type="slide" position="29">
	<title>No computer, just a conversation</title>

	<content>
	<text>Dr. Card is very upset and eventually asks if she can start the consult over at her computer.Think about the way Dr. Card came into the room. She really wanted to dig in and figure things out. She identified her learning style as hands-on. Having a conversation with a hands-on learner is usually not enough.</text>

	<text>$$card_grumpy_meter$$</text>
</content>
</section>
<section type="slide" position="30">
	<title>Starting with the Basics</title>

	<content>
	<text>You recall your training and want to lay the foundation by describing the fundatmentals. You start with pixels.Dr. Card is sitting at the computer, ready to go. She wants to jump in.</text>

	<text>$$card_grumpy_meter$$</text>
</content>

	<related-content>It is a common mistake to get excited by a client who seems to be &quot;tech savvy&quot;.; It&apos;s important for you to determine if clients are enthusiats who know a few keywords, or; if the are truly experts in the subject matter you are consulting.</related-content>
</section>
<section type="slide" position="31">
	<title>Pixels: Select How to Describe</title>

	<content></content>
</section>
<section type="slide" position="32">
	<title>A pixel is a physical point</title>

	<content>
	<text>Dr. Card looks at you with utter confusion and needs further explanation.Although this response is technically accurate, it is too, well, technical. Never use a consultation as an opportunity to display what you know. You should take all that you know and work hard on translating it instead.</text>

	<text>$$card_grumpy_meter$$</text>
</content>
</section>
<section type="slide" position="33">
	<title>A minute area of illumination</title>

	<content>
	<text>Dr. Card is completely engaged and nods in a way that shows she underdstands.This response is still technical, but not too technical. You are using phrases that most people have encountered. Everyone knows screens, images, and light.</text>

	<text>$$card_grumpy_meter$$</text>
</content>

	<related-content>This is just the right level of technological terms for Dr. Card. She is not an expert,; but she has been around a tech blog or two and has done a bit of research. Good job gauging the right level of “geek speak”.</related-content>
</section>
<section type="slide" position="34">
	<title>Dots used to make a picture</title>

	<content>
	<text>Dr. Card is getting a little fidgety and bored at the same time. Ultimately she gets impatient and asks if you can move on to the next topic.</text>

	<text>$$card_grumpy_meter$$</text>
</content>

	<related-content>Dr. Card is getting bored. This response is not technical enough. She already knows this and wants you to move on.; This is an example of the balance you need as a consultant. Too much tech info and some clients are overwhelmed. Not enough and your &quot;geekier&quot; clients may get bored.</related-content>
</section>
<section type="slide" position="35">
	<title>Grumpy Meter Check</title>

	<content>
	<text>This is a quick check on Dr. Card’s Grumpy meter. Please remember, the higher the number, the grumpier she is.</text>

	<text>$$card_grumpy_meter$$</text>
</content>
</section>
<section type="slide" position="36">
	<title>Pixels: Select How to Describe</title>

	<content></content>
</section>
<section type="slide" position="37">
	<title>Fast</title>

	<content>
	<text>Dr. Card is trying to keep up but is having to ask you to repeat phrases and back up to re-explain.Cognitive overload is a major concern when you start talking to fast. It takes a while to process new information and if you are quickly moving from one subject to the next, your client may not have learned the last concept.</text>

	<text>$$card_grumpy_meter$$</text>
</content>
</section>
<section type="slide" position="38">
	<title>Slow</title>

	<content>
	<text>Dr. Card is getting bored and fidgety. She wants you to talk faster so she can get to working with video. She is frustrated.A slow rate may be just right for complete novices, but annoying for clients with some skills.</text>

	<text>$$card_grumpy_meter$$</text>
</content>
</section>
<section type="slide" position="39">
	<title>Steady</title>

	<content>
	<text>Dr. Card happily clicks away at the computer while you explain concepts at just the right rate.Some times steady is just right and some times it is too fast.</text>

	<text>$$card_grumpy_meter$$</text>
</content>
</section>
<section type="slide" position="40">
	<title>Grumpy Meter Check</title>

	<content>
	<text>This is a quick check on both faculty members’ grumpy meter.</text>

	<text>$$card_grumpy_meter$$</text>

	<text>$$page_grumpy_meter$$</text>
</content>
</section>
<section type="slide" position="41">
	<title>Results</title>

	<content>
	<text>$$card_grumpy_meter$$</text>

	<text>$$page_grumpy_meter$$</text>
</content>
</section>
<section type="slide" position="42">
	<title>Reflection</title>

	<content>
	<text>Take a few moments to think about how Dr. Page and Dr. Card were different? How were they similar?What did you learn about learning preferences?Is there a perfect way to describe something to everyone?How did you have to change your style between the two faculty members?This was a relatively simple scenario, but think about some fo the interactions you have had. Who are your Dr. Pages? Who are your Dr. Cards?</text>
</content>
</section>
<section type="slide" position="43">
	<title>Summary</title>

	<content>
	<text>Review of Learning ObjectivesExplain video terminology using more than one analogyObserve and respond to patron’s visual cues of confusion if presentProvide alternative explanations to terminology if patron does not understandDescribe video manipulation processes at a rate that allows for patron absorptionFinal Summary</text>

	<text>$$card_grumpy_meter$$</text>

	<text>$$page_grumpy_meter$$</text>
</content>
</section>
<section type="slide" position="44">
	<title></title>

	<content></content>

	<related-content>You have reache the end of this scenario, but it is not done yet.; Please retake this scenario multiple times so you can see the various reactions.; Dr. Page and Dr. Card have to your responses. It&apos;s important to understand why people react the way they do.; to various bits of information and instruction.; Thank you for participating and I hope to see you soon.</related-content>
</section>
</document-metadata>
